Samuel B. Smith, III

■ 4600 W. Guadalupe St. B302 Austin, Tx 78751 ■ Phone: 956-371-7760 ■ Email: Samtrey@gmail.com

SUMMARY

Former scientist turned web developer who's passionate about creating fluid applications that utilize the latest technologies. Experienced developing across the stack, I equally revel designing pixel perfect front ends and clean efficient back ends. With a diverse technical background I bring strong problem solving skills, and the ability to strive in multidisciplinary team environments.

EDUCATION

The University of Texas at Austin - Full Stack Web Developer Bootcamp

07/2016 - 2/2017

Six month full stack developer course covering:
Javascript, HTML, CSS, jQuery, Responsive Design, Bootstrap, Materialize, React.js, Node.js, MongoDB, Laravel, MySQL, Heroku, security and session storage, and user authentication.

The University of Texas at Austin

08/2009 - 12/2013

Bachelor of Science in Environmental Science and Sustainability

WORK EXPERIENCE

Equipment Technician – Exploration Instruments LLC

05/2014- Current

- Develop novel testing procedures that ensures greater equipment reliability, preventing costly shipment of replacement parts to customers.
- Repair damaged equipment, manufacturing replacement parts when possible. Systems range in cost from tens to hundred of thousands of dollars, and repairs made in house save thousands in time and money.

Laboratory Research Assistant II Fire Ant Laboratory – The University of Texas at Austin

05/2012 - 08/2013

- Administered data collection and analysis for two laboratory research projects
 - 1) Described the colonial distribution and pathogen susceptibility in *Solenopsis invicta*.
 - 2) Attempted to record the life history of a novel and undescribed species of parasitic fly.
- Responsible for laboratory maintenance, equipment sterilization, and maintaining the formicary.

Senate Messenger – The Texas State Senate

01/2009 - 05/2009

- Provided administrative aid in Senate committee meetings and Senate Chamber.
- Responsible for delivering correspondence between Senate offices.

INTERNSHIPS

Intern – Environmental Science Institute (ESI), The University of Texas at Austin

09/2013 – 12/2013

- Generated Environmental Science student cohort profiles for the ESI website.
- Provided support for Hot Science Cool Talks events and performed standard office duties.

Intern –Texas State Senator Eddie Lucio, Jr – 2009 Legislative Session

01/2009 - 05/2009

- Assisted in committee meetings and provided general office support.
- Received constituents and handled correspondence by phone and mail.

Intern – Fundacion Quipus La Paz, Bolivia

03/2007 – 06/2007

- Collaborated on research towards the application of thin client networks built with legacy hardware and open source software.
- Thin client networks would allow schools and internet cafes in developing nations to affordably maintain.

PROJECTS & COURSEWORK

GitHub Repository

Please browse for an example of previous and current projects: https://github.com/sbs863

Senior Research Thesis

- Designed and executed an extensive field survey and sampling program to determine the distribution of mound densities, social forms, and pathogen infection of <u>Solenopsis invicta</u> (Red imported fire ant) across an eighty-two acre habitat.
- Full scientific write up including a complete analysis and interpretation of data and a spatial analysis via ArcGIS.